Guide to the Scholars of the House Program, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Student essays and projects, circa 1963-1985; Accession 19ND-A-383
  - Watters, Wellington D.: The Italian cityscape in the late middle ages and the Renaissance., 1977 (Box 4)
  - Osterman, Steven Douglas: Dark and deep. America and the ethics of world poverty, health and hunger, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Bader, Michael B.: The politics of famine relief and rehabilitation in Ethiopia, 1973-1976., 1977 (Box 4)
  - King, William Davies: Four performances, Text of the performances, poems and texts of preliminary presentations., 1977 (Box 4)
  - Reese, William S.: Winnowers of the past: The Americanist tradition in the nineteenth century, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Farrar, Curtis: The Impact of the Power Struggle on American Labor Policy, undated (Box 5)
  - Cohen, Fred E.: Protein Folding: Mathematical Models for the Transition from Secondary to Tertiary Structure, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Herlands, Louis: Chromatin Structure, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Meyer, Peter N.: M.G.M. and the Studio System in the Age of Mass Production, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Ortel, Charles K.: The Making of Modern Kenya, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Robison, Gregory F.: Claustra Monasterii: A Day in a Late Twelfth-century Cistercian Monastery, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Sands, Stephen: Singing for Generations Unborn: An Investigation into the Traditional Religion of the Oglala Sioux, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Stone, Jonathan: "Fermata" and Other Stories, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Tauxe, Lisa: A Comparison of Isochrons Defined by Short-Term Paleomagnetic Events and Lithostratigraphic Units in Siwalik Rocks of the Potwar Plateau, Punjab Province, Pakistan, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Brenner, Carl: "Spheres," musical composition; "Flashback," musical composition, 1978 (Box 1A)
  - Young, Jesse Allen: A century of blacks at Yale, 1874-1974, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Austin, Sam: American Gothic, [1979] (Box 9)
  - Chao, Philip: Clonal analysis of development in Drosophilia melanogaster: The larval salivary glands do not develop by compartmentalization, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Gibbons, Nathaniel: An illustrated guide to the regional geology of Connecticut, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Moeller, Susan R.: French caricature from the February Revolution to the Commune (1848-1871): Charles Philipon, Honore Daumier, Nadar and Andre Gill, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Moeller, Susan R.: But Can She Type?, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Shafir, Mark: The New Political Theory: Critique and Reconstruction, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Wehrli, Catherine: [Twelve slides of art works], 1979 (Box 10)
  - Bain, William M.: VEGE: A Natural Language Query System, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Gibbs, Robert: Words in the Soul: Seeking a Transcendent Measure for Human Language, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Kelly, Kate: Music in Later Medieval Ireland: A Study of the Sources, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Kiesling, Stephen H.: The Shell Game, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Rycenga, Jennifer: Anne Boleyn, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Cross, William R.: Observations on three of Palladio's decorated villas, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Gabriel, Kent W.: "Selected contributions leading to the recognition of mitochondrial substructure and its importance in oxidative phosphorylation", 1981 (Box 14)
  - Baker, Charles Marx: Our liberty most dear, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Rosario, Sonia Yvette: Doble vida/ A double life [video cassette], 1981 (Box 14)
  - Barash, Carol Lynn: The letting go: A memoir [Closed until 2031], 1981 (Box 15)
  - O'Brien, Sarah Dabney: Individual instances, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Bundy, Caroline Lawrence: The sense that we remain, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Chandra, Premala: A study of completely integrable systems, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Gregory, Gina Lynn: The Jewish Hospital and Medical Center of Brooklyn, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Hughes, Ian Hugo: [Twelve colored transparencies of paintings], 1981 (Box 17)
  - Mennona, Joseph A., Jr.: Hope. A work for pre-recorded and live ensembles in four movements [with three tapes], 1981 (Box 17)
  - Snead, James A.: Repetition in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg: Toward the Hermetic Novel, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Andrew, Joseph: Survivor Bound: A Novel, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Bowling, Allen C.: Micromolar Affinity Benzodiazepine Receptors: Identification and Characterization in the Central Nervous System, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Brown, Scott E.: A Case of Mistaken Identity: The Life and Music of James P. Johnson, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Corbett, Bill: An Exploration of Playwriting Through Practice: Three Original Plays and Commentary, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Holcombe, Steven D.: In Jesus' Name, We Pray - Amen, first and second drafts; The Cleaning Woman and Interruption; Practice in Writing Screenplays: Spectacle Son et Lumiere dy Chade l'Institute de Touraine, Several Short Films, Scenes of Hawthorne's The Scarlet Letter, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Hylton, Kevin N.: Slides of paintings, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Kajimoto, Izumi: Daisuke and the Deities: A Novel, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Peterson, Vincent R.: Crossin' Over: Close Readings in the Fiction of Zora Neale Hurston, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Shapiro, Miles: B.: A Novel, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Thomas, Lorella: Harold Nicolson, 1927-1939, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Williams, Tony: Toward the Neighborhood Ideal, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Green, Ruth S.: Intrados, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Barrett, Kedron: 8 oil paintings by Kedron Barrett, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Ettinger, Maia: Homophobia: Three essays, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Bysiewicz, Susan: Ella: a political biography of Ella Grasso, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Saleh, Javed Bin: An analysis of the agrarian structure of Bangladesh based on farm-level data, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Lee, Nelson, editor: Unpublished organ works of Joan Cabanilles (1644-1712) and his contemporaries. Edited by Nelson Lee., 1983 (Box 23)
  - Cochran, Kevin: Sawdust in the attic. Written and designed by Kevin Cochran, 1983 (Box 24)
  - McCany, Laura: Two Stories: The Yow Milker and That Face in the Mirror, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Edelson, David: In A Word. A mixed-media concert, Harkness Auditorium. Video tape, 1985 (Box 25)
  - Ehrlick, Jonathan and Robin Pogrebin: "Parkington and Me" Video tape of play., 1985 (Box 25)
    General
    See also: Box 54 #70
  - Swartz, Andrew F.: "Sign Language Research: An analysis of the vocabulary of American Sign Language" Humanities Program, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Werdell, Philip R.: "The Forgotten Sumner: Icons of an Iconoclast - An Intellectual Biography of William Graham Sumner", 1963 (Box 25)
  - Ehrlick, Jonathan and Robin Pogrebin: "Parkington and Me" See also: Box 53 #67, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Churbuck, David C.: "Parallel Roundings", 1980 (Box 26)
  - Reprints: These published essays which are portions of, or based on Scholar of the House Essays, are placed with the original work.
    - Menafee, Samuel P.: "The 'Countless Stones': A final reckoning," Folklore. V.86, Autumn/Winter 1975. p.146-166
      General note
      See Series I Box 41
    - Newberger, Eli H.: "The transition from ragtime to improvised piano style," Journal of Jazz Studies, v.3, no.2, Spring 1976. p.[3]-18
    - Newberger, Eli H.: "Archetypes and antecedents of piano blues and boogie woogie style," Journal of Jazz Studies, v.4, no.1, Fall 1976. p.[84]-109.
- Records of the chairman, 1968-1975; Accession 1975-A-012
  Restricted until January 1, 2045.
  - Papers of the Chariman of the Scholar of the House Program: correspondence, reports, subject proposals, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
- Student essays and projects, 1982; Accession 1982-A-031
  - Joseph Andrew, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faul Rloodgood, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen Bowling, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scott Brown, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William D. Corbett, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Steven Holcomb, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kevin N. Hylton, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Izumi Kajimoto, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miles J. Shapiro, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lorella Thomas, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anthony Williams, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Scholar and program records and scholars essays, circa 1974-1981; Accession 1994-A-123
  Restricted until January 1, 2069
  - Program Records
    - BCC- J.E. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Scholar of the House, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Scholar of the House, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Scholar of the House, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Scholar of the House Budget(s), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Scholar of the House Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Scholars of the House, Budgets, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Scholars' Budgets, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Scholar of the House, Correspondence, External, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Scholar of the House Exam Reader, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Exam Reports, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Scholar of the House: Mechanics (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Scholar of the House Operating, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Scholar of the House Operations, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Scholar of the House Operating File, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Scholar of the House Register (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Report, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Essays
    - Carolyn Elhe: Behavior and Ecology of Brachyphylla Cavernaruma and Artibeus Jamaicensis, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Wellington Watters: The Italian Cihscape in the Late Middle Ages and the Renaissance, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Peter Meyer: M-G-M and the Studio System in the Ane of Mass Production, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Christopher Maher: Bloom, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Jennifer Rycenga: Anne Boleyn, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Jennifer Rycenga: Compositions of Jennifer Rycenga, circa 1977 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Charles Baker: Our Liberty Most Dear, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Pramala Chandra: A Study of Completely Intengrabe Systems, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Gina Gregory: The Jewish Hospital and Medical Center of Brooklyn, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Linda Brothers: Mississippi (Box 4, Folder 89)